[{"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339806", "question": "By what name is the musician, Charles Hardin, better known as?", "answer": "Buddy Holly", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a378", "question": "What is the capital of Finland?", "answer": "Helsinki", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5f3057fb5aa2bc17b61b2ad4", "question": "Which fresh water fish has the Latin name \"Esox Lucius\"?", "answer": "Northern Pike", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339aad", "question": "What popular children\u2019s book did Forrest Gump keep in his briefcase?", "answer": "Curious George", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59049ddecf93664eb10486b1", "question": "What year was the original film \"Friday the 13th\" released?", "answer": "1980", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133adf9", "question": "What was the first building in the world to have more than 100 floors?", "answer": "Empire State Building", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397f5", "question": "Who wrote the song \"Mr Tambourine Man\"?", "answer": "Bob Dylan", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd75ae347d002c297e4c2", "question": "What is the only continent without native reptiles and snakes?", "answer": "Antarctica", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a740", "question": "Albuquerque is located on the shores of what river?", "answer": "Rio Grande River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a4a1", "question": "Which mountain is the highest in Australia?", "answer": "Mount Kosciuszko", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b942", "question": "What are spit in the annual contest in Paul's Valley, Oklahoma?", "answer": "Watermelon seeds", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339927", "question": "In what film does Jack Nicholson famously say, \u201cHeeeeere\u2019s Johnny!\u201d?", "answer": "The Shining", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c8af", "question": "Luna orbits what planet of the solar system?", "answer": "Earth", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa0f", "question": "What is the most westerly capital city in mainland Europe?", "answer": "Lisbon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339fa2", "question": "What rock epic begins \"The screen door slams, Mary's dress sways\"?", "answer": "Thunder Road", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a3", "question": "What song off of their \"Joshua Tree\" album was the band U2\u2019s first #1 hit on the US charts?", "answer": "With or Without You", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5be5809f5415ba52ed6f0ab6", "question": "What document is typically needed for one to enter a foreign country?", "answer": "A passport", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe69b9820565ad31a57c761", "question": "Jimmy Carter served in which military branch?", "answer": "U.S. Navy", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afee", "question": "George Washington was born in which present-day state?", "answer": "Virginia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59decf57ea2747c8aff16d1d", "question": "Junko Tabei was the first woman to reach what?", "answer": "Summit of Mount Everest", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fea3e5cff048f679a45ab5a", "question": "What disease does an endocrinologist generally study?", "answer": "Diabetes", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339969", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", what grade does Edna Krabappel teach?", "answer": "Fourth grade", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fea43d8ff048f679a45ab89", "question": "What is the scientific study of human movement?", "answer": "Kinesiology", "category": "science"}, {"id": "60023f1e4be4723ccac22162", "question": "What is tallest dog breed in the world?", "answer": "Irish Wolfhound", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0cf", "question": "During the Civil War, what iron-clad ship engaged in battle with the \"CSS Virginia\"?", "answer": "The \"Monitor\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a488", "question": "William Mynors is the captain that discovered and named what island in 1643?", "answer": "Christmas Island", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133aecd", "question": "What US general accepted the surrender of Japan?", "answer": "General Douglas MacArthur", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5ad7ebc7b24f84e0b9f9ffe0", "question": "Which drummer led a band called \"The Jazz Messengers\"?", "answer": "Art Blakey", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133986e", "question": "In Disney's \"Peter Pan\", what animal is Captain Hook constantly stalked by?", "answer": "A crocodile", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fecd201ec223966ae8f88c2", "question": "How many visible cuts are there in the 2014 film \"Birdman\"?", "answer": "16", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe13266e39efa6330e0feda", "question": "Where was windsurfing invented?", "answer": "USA", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b5f1", "question": "Who gained notoriety in 1997 for her relationship with Vili Fualaau?", "answer": "Mary Kay Letourneau", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a2", "question": "What forest was home to Robin Hood?", "answer": "The Sherwood Forest", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe937656bd93ce3a4e5f66c", "question": "Cyberphobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Computers", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c64d", "question": "What animal lives in a lodge?", "answer": "The Beaver", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c546", "question": "What is the most popular animal eaten before it's born and after it's dead?", "answer": "Chicken", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7bb", "question": "In miles, approximately, how much Atlantic coastline does the state of New Hampshire have?", "answer": "18", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339756", "question": "What city was the setting of the TV show \"Friends\"?", "answer": "New York", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "591c3813815febcc896f9279", "question": "What is the eigth sign of the Zodiac?", "answer": "Scorpio", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c16b", "question": "In which European city are the headquarters of OPEC?", "answer": "Vienna", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ccf7b0eb37b32637bdc44c4", "question": "In what year was the first opera created?", "answer": "1597", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bb70", "question": "Who led the NFL in rushing yards four out of five years from 1972 to 1976?", "answer": "O.J. Simpson", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fe8f3d601dd7bf43be5e818", "question": "OSHA stands for what in the US?", "answer": "Occupational Safety and Health Administration", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133995f", "question": "Who played Angela Bower on the TV show \"Who\u2019s the Boss\"?", "answer": "Judith Light", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff25b8031a458464a93c478", "question": "In what year was the McDonald's Happy Meal created?", "answer": "Originally fielded in 1977 and ultimately released nationwide in 1979", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339ba1", "question": "What famous movie actor got his start playing the first openly gay nationally broadcast TV character, in the late 1970's?", "answer": "Billy Crystal", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b342", "question": "Who patented the safety razor in 1895?", "answer": "King Gillette", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a602", "question": "Which US state is home to Guadalupe Mountains National Park?", "answer": "Texas", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b403", "question": "Who was the second man to walk on the Moon?", "answer": "Buzz Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338cbb", "question": "Who wrote \"Breakfast at Tiffany's\"?", "answer": "Truman Capote", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c2e7", "question": "What is the longest insect?", "answer": "The walking stick", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b1f1", "question": "Who was the only two-term president of the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "Sam Houston", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe65cb41f3c0ead6880d617", "question": "In what country did the concept of Easter bunny originate?", "answer": "Germany", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399a0", "question": "What legendary cartoon producers first names were William and Joseph?", "answer": "Hanna-Barbera", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133ba02", "question": "Who was John Updike?", "answer": "An author", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58d118a04fea7fe947a22286", "question": "Which novel did Joseph Heller write as a sequel to \"Catch-22\"?", "answer": "Closing Time", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9c8", "question": "Which US state has the least rainfall?", "answer": "Nevada", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339a06", "question": "Who was the lead singer of the band Soundgarden?", "answer": "Chris Cornell", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113396ac", "question": "What popular film director/actor co-wrote the 1994 movie \"Natural Born Killers\"?", "answer": "Quentin Tarantino", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390bb", "question": "Which English author created Inspector Morse?", "answer": "Colin Dexter", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b143", "question": "Who was the first US President to be impeached by the US House of Representatives?", "answer": "Andrew Johnson", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b571b1967df192a942e3364", "question": "What is the name of the dog on the Cracker Jack box?", "answer": "Bingo", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c93a", "question": "What fish has green bones?", "answer": "Garfish", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113391d5", "question": "Which band is known in Spain as U-Dos?", "answer": "U2", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b73c", "question": "Located on Central Avenue in Louisville, Kentucky, what is the name of the race track where the Kentucky Derby is held?", "answer": "Churchill Downs", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5922032ba4edfd43a087ade1", "question": "Whose autobiography is titled \"Long Walk to Freedom\"?", "answer": "Nelson Mandela's", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "590720d03745b36be73039f3", "question": "What year did Disney release a 3D motion-capture adaptation of \"A Christmas Carol\"?", "answer": "2009", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe69f9120565ad31a57c78d", "question": "What sport\u2019s first non-military competition was hosted in Norway in 1868?", "answer": "Downhill skiing", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a05d", "question": "What is the name of the genetically modified dinosaur in the 2015 movie \"Jurassic World\"?", "answer": "Indominus Rex", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b116", "question": "Who was the second man to set foot on the moon?", "answer": "Edwin \"Buzz\" Aldrin", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a81e", "question": "In what state was the transcontinental railroad completed in 1869, with the hammering of the Golden Spike?", "answer": "Utah", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339066", "question": "What does the Latin word \"Verbatim\" literally means?", "answer": "Word for word", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c24", "question": "Who wrote \"The Star-Spangled Banner\"?", "answer": "Francis Scott Key", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a7cd", "question": "Which US state is nicknamed the \"Green Mountain State\"?", "answer": "Vermont", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b7abafb6490a8cc1a6e5292", "question": "In Roman numerals, what number does \"D\" represent?", "answer": "500", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a42e", "question": "Which ocean is between South America and Africa?", "answer": "Atlantic", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133921b", "question": "What instrument did Sting play with the band \"The Police\"?", "answer": "Bass guitar", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b950", "question": "What holiday do Americans celebrate on the third Monday in January?", "answer": "Martin Luther King Jr. Day", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1d6", "question": "What two ingredients are used to make the standard Stinger cocktail?", "answer": "Cognac and white creme de menthe", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113399ec", "question": "What was the name of Esther Rolles\u2019 character on both the TV shows \"Maude\" and \"Good Times\"?", "answer": "Florida", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "601b4abb49076251badbeabb", "question": "Where is the oldest African-American theater located in the U.S.?", "answer": "Cleveland, Ohio -- Karamu House opened to the public in 1915. The name is Swahili, meaning \"a place of joyful gathering\".", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe4e12a06d333868d34d724", "question": "Which Roman Emperor\u2019s \"Edict of Milan\" made Christianity legal?", "answer": "Constantine I", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a667", "question": "What land mass juts into the northern end of Delaware Bay?", "answer": "Cape May", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5ff14015b0ee8c595b6d3994", "question": "In what city was the Diary of Anne Frank written?", "answer": "Amsterdam", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fec8db1ec223966ae8f8856", "question": "The character Travis Bickle is from what movie?", "answer": "\"Taxi Driver\"", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abf9", "question": "What country is the Mekong Delta located in?", "answer": "Vietnam", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe378ce0ada16518afdc054", "question": "Which popular Christmas song was originally written for a Broadway musical?", "answer": "\"White Christmas\"", "category": "history"}, {"id": "58dba16a874c93a3298b2126", "question": "What is Kenny G's real surname?", "answer": "Gorelick", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5b3232eebf195a31e15d7395", "question": "What movie marked Jodie Foster's directorial debut?", "answer": "Little Man Tate", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8aeed01dd7bf43be5e784", "question": "How long is the hour hand on Big Ben?", "answer": "9 feet", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113392e8", "question": "In the movie \"The Terminator\", what did the cyborg remove in order to repair itself?", "answer": "Its eyeball", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fd9717923c87fd04dd15e4c", "question": "Who organized the Boston Tea Party?", "answer": "Samuel Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fd81c48d0de9af39e9d4682", "question": "Who was the first U.S. president to be photographed?", "answer": "John Quincy Adams", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c6c", "question": "What is the name of the sequel to the 1977 movie \"Saturday Night Fever\"?", "answer": "Staying Alive", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfff", "question": "Who is known as \"Big Mama\" in ladies pro golf?", "answer": "JoAnne Carner", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393a5", "question": "What bones did James Dean break in the movie \"Rebel Without A Cause\"?", "answer": "His knuckles", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "6015e05cfe83fe1f2a824b8b", "question": "What German political leader was known as the \"Iron Chancellor\"?", "answer": "Otto von Bismarck", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a37a", "question": "What is the capital of Portugal?", "answer": "Lisbon", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe131f2e39efa6330e0fed9", "question": "Where is the world\u2019s biggest ballet school?", "answer": "Cuba", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338e1c", "question": "What famed object from mythology did the Venus de Milo hold in her now-missing left hand?", "answer": "The golden apple of Paris", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b871", "question": "What prominent facial feature is Hello Kitty missing?", "answer": "Mouth", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388a8", "question": "Who wrote the novel 1984?", "answer": "George Orwell", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bddc", "question": "What ingredient gives Cajun \"dirty rice\" its dark color?", "answer": "Chicken liver or giblets", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc32", "question": "What color is the saffron spice?", "answer": "Yellow-orange", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c1c", "question": "Which year was the first book in the Harry Potter series published?", "answer": "1997", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58dba40a874c93a3298b2142", "question": "Puccini's \"Tosca\" is based on which 1887 Victorien Sardou play?", "answer": "La Tosca", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c916", "question": "What does a zoologist study?", "answer": "Animals", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113397a6", "question": "What name did Nathaniel Dwayne Hale adopt, to hype his pedigree as Snoop Dogg's cousin?", "answer": "Nate Dogg", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff3cfb24f032c0db195b492", "question": "How many \"enemies of the revolution\" were officially executed during the Reign of Terror?", "answer": "16,594", "category": "history"}, {"id": "6017349944491cbd7c5a1781", "question": "What is he maximum number of years a US president can serve in office?", "answer": "Ten years -- If he or she inherited the office after a president died or was removed with two years or less remaining in the term, he can serve two more full terms. Otherwise they are limited to one full term.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c28b", "question": "Which ear can most people hear better with?", "answer": "The right", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a88f", "question": "In what country would you find the port of Rosetta?", "answer": "Egypt", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa7c", "question": "What is the capital of Zimbabwe?", "answer": "Harare", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fde4df1c6c6b019850c9a83", "question": "Who said \"it is far safer to be feared than loved\"?", "answer": "Niccolo Machiavelli", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe8fe9a01dd7bf43be5e85c", "question": "What does \"Veni, vidi, vici\" translate into?", "answer": "I came, I saw, I conquered.", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133af7a", "question": "What scandal forced US President Richard Nixon to resign in 1974?", "answer": "Watergate Scandal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388ab", "question": "What is the one-eyed giant of Greek mythology?", "answer": "Cyclops", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338d8f", "question": "What original literary work was the movie \"The Door in the Floor\" based on?", "answer": "A Widow for One Year", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58d117474fea7fe947a22278", "question": "Yerevan is the capital of which country?", "answer": "Armenia", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fbaee2c0738315b1fb74e32", "question": "Who are Quagmire\u2019s daughters in the TV show \"Family Guy\"", "answer": "Anna Lee and Courtney", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ab99bb621a8909e5c332d2e", "question": "What novel was the 1988 film \"Who Framed Roger Rabbit\" loosely based on?", "answer": "Who Censored Roger Rabbit?", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b481", "question": "What year did the Franco-Prussian War begin?", "answer": "1870", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c846", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the fovea?", "answer": "The eye", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe3e99b38e4e5d4832e6311", "question": "According to the Bible, who killed more people at his death than in his life?", "answer": "Samson", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bdbb", "question": "What animal was used in British coal mines until being phased out in 1986?", "answer": "Canaries", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a3", "question": "In which decade were the first Winter Olympic Games held?", "answer": "1920s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1c2", "question": "Which politician is known as Tarzan?", "answer": "Michael Heseltine", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b437", "question": "What wonder stood over 30 metres high in the Rhodes harbour?", "answer": "Colossus of Rhodes", "category": "history"}, {"id": "59008c7ecf842fa4c4ba969f", "question": "In which novel would you find reference to the \"Cracks of Doom\"?", "answer": "The Lord of the Rings", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4cf", "question": "What name is given to trees that lose their leaves annually?", "answer": "Deciduous", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5f95b02755722f97b22684db", "question": "What does Dumbledore give to Ron in his will?", "answer": "Deluminator", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113390c3", "question": "Who wrote the horror novel \"Dracula\"?", "answer": "Bram Stoker", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5afad88e430e050a5df0d112", "question": "Which brand of soda was the second to be produced by The Coca-Cola Company?", "answer": "Fanta", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339657", "question": "In the TV show \"The Simpsons\", the words across the front of the Springfield museum say \"Truth, Knowledge and...\" what?", "answer": "Gift shop", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59ded01fea2747c8aff16d23", "question": "In which sport is the America's Cup awarded?", "answer": "Sailboat racing", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b6ae", "question": "Which side of a ship is \"port\"?", "answer": "Left", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b529", "question": "What does the abbreviation WWW stand for?", "answer": "World Wide Web", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339edc", "question": "What position was first held by Caesar Augustus?", "answer": "Emperor of Rome", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "595244e2736d4be723796b6a", "question": "How many scents can the human nose detect?", "answer": "More than 1 Trillion", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fefa3c86ce05a3942286ea9", "question": "Which famous writer was San Francisco's first Black female streetcar conductor?", "answer": "Maya Angelou", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339226", "question": "What country provided most of the settings for \"The Lord of the Rings\" movies?", "answer": "New Zealand", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f03113395ef", "question": "In The Simpsons, which immigrant in Springfield actually got deported once?", "answer": "Groundskeeper Willie", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a6ba", "question": "What city is home to the headquarters of the Boeing Company?", "answer": "Chicago", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fe7d06b877e98cb97778a61", "question": "Guadalcanal is located in what group of islands?", "answer": "The Solomon Islands", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a992", "question": "What river flows through Jackson Hole, Wyoming?", "answer": "The Snake River", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133ad23", "question": "What country did french fries come from?", "answer": "Belgium", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c4af", "question": "The flowers known as rhododendrons are most commonly shaped like what?", "answer": "Bells", "category": "science"}, {"id": "58d077f4870e6f05ba600869", "question": "What role did Matthew McConaughey play in the 1995 film \"Boys on the Side\"?", "answer": "Abe Lincoln", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b9d", "question": "What is the profession of Jon Cryer's character on the TV show \"Two and a Half Men\"?", "answer": "Chiropractor", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339201", "question": "In what movie does Redfoot flick his cigarette into the face of McManus?", "answer": "The Usual Suspects", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9df", "question": "Which branch of science is concerned with the study of matter and energy?", "answer": "Physics", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe4e13806d333868d34d725", "question": "Which African nation successfully resisted colonialism in the late 19th century?", "answer": "Ethiopia", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338edb", "question": "What famous horse belonged to Don Quixote?", "answer": "Rocinante", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339b2c", "question": "In \"Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs\", which dwarf has the longest beard?", "answer": "Sleepy", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133bafd", "question": "In what year was Howard Hughes born?", "answer": "1905", "category": "general"}, {"id": "58c9f74cb4e2c7fbd3896747", "question": "In the beer world, what does the abbreviation F.G. stand for?", "answer": "Final gravity", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a72f", "question": "The Simi Valley is located in which US state?", "answer": "California", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a2cb", "question": "Who played the female lead in the 1947 film \"The Bishop's Wife\"?", "answer": "Loretta Young", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339782", "question": "\"Skyrim\" is the fifth installment in which video game series?", "answer": "The Elder Scrolls", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e48", "question": "What athlete had a part in the movie \"The Naked Gun\"?", "answer": "O. J. Simpson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339e88", "question": "What future celebrity made an appearance as Iris in \"Taxi Driver\"?", "answer": "Jodie Foster", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339943", "question": "What is the first rule in the movie \"Fight Club\"?", "answer": "You don't talk about Fight Club", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc68", "question": "What college did Brett Favre attend and play football for?", "answer": "Southern Mississippi", "category": "general"}, {"id": "600241d94be4723ccac2217e", "question": "In the book \"The Hunt for Red October,\" how is the Soviet submarine V. K. Konovalov destroyed?", "answer": "Reactor meltdown", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c032", "question": "Pyrophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fire", "category": "general"}, {"id": "6008dbabf4f3bc4a292f8619", "question": "Which country was the first to recognize the Republic of Texas?", "answer": "France (In 1841, France opened a legation in Austin and the Republic of Texas opened an embassy in Paris.)", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133902a", "question": "Whose Romantic odes include \"Ode to Melancholy\" and \"Ode on a Grecian Urn\"?", "answer": "John Keats", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338a81", "question": "Edie Sedgwick was a protege of what artist?", "answer": "Andy Warhol", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fe4e72306d333868d34d73a", "question": "How old was Josiah when he became King?", "answer": "8", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a14b", "question": "Who is the youngest member of the band Boyzone?", "answer": "Ronan Keating", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c1e7", "question": "Who is more commonly known as the Michelin Man?", "answer": "Bibendum", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5909d038bb53d1af658864f9", "question": "Which Canadian Prime Minister was born on December 25, 1971?", "answer": "Justin Trudeau", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f530ff048f679a45aad3", "question": "Nyctophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Darkness", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fea7b11ff048f679a45abf1", "question": "What kind of animal is a \"klipspringer\"?", "answer": "An African antelope", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bd30", "question": "Where was the first FIFA World Cup held?", "answer": "Uruguay", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338de9", "question": "From what language did English borrow the word \"wok\"?", "answer": "Cantonese", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a38a", "question": "In which state is the Grand Canyon located in?", "answer": "Arizona", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339c42", "question": "Mort Goldman is the father of which supporting character in the TV show \"Family Guy\"?", "answer": "Neil Goldman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5e8a88fa404ad935a7e1a63e", "question": "Which composer began to lose his hearing at age 26?", "answer": "Ludwig van Beethoven", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a251", "question": "Who was the female star of the 1992 film \"Basic Instinct\"?", "answer": "Sharon Stone", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339577", "question": "What is Scrooge's first name?", "answer": "Ebenezer", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cc8", "question": "Who had a surprise cameo as \"Agent M\" in \"Men in Black II\"?", "answer": "Michael Jackson", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a130", "question": "Who played the Spirit of Christmas in the 1988 TV film \"Blackadder's Christmas Carol'\"?", "answer": "Robbie Coltrane", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133981b", "question": "What was the first American film to show a toilet flushing?", "answer": "Psycho", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a586", "question": "What is the capital of the US state of Iowa?", "answer": "Des Moines", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b0f6", "question": "What two words were added to the US \"Pledge of Allegiance\" in 1954?", "answer": "Under God", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133948f", "question": "How long did the 1929 Academy Award ceremony last?", "answer": "15 minutes", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5af25af1b63e5727cf5a4857", "question": "The song \"(Everything I Do) I Do It for You\" was the title track to which film?", "answer": "Robin Hood: Prince of Thieves", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a01f", "question": "Which of the two leads of 1995's movie \"Friday\" didn't appear in either of the sequels?", "answer": "Chris Tucker", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bc0f", "question": "What was Wayne Gretzky's jersey number during his professional hockey career?", "answer": "99", "category": "general"}, {"id": "597cd92ce347d002c297e4cb", "question": "What is \"Three King's Day\" also known as?", "answer": "Epiphany", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cca", "question": "What kind of gem is El Corazon which is \"romanced\" in the movie \"Romancing the Stone\"?", "answer": "An emerald", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b191", "question": "What year was Napoleon Bonaparte born?", "answer": "1769", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388f0", "question": "In the book \"Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince\", who does Harry catch tentacula leaves?", "answer": "Professor Horace Slughorn", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339cb0", "question": "What breed of dog is Santa's Little Helper?", "answer": "Greyhound", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a9dc", "question": "On which island will you find \"Adams Peak\"?", "answer": "Sri Lanka", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5b358a0b5db0d66a186cb550", "question": "Which ocean does the African country, Burundi, has access to?", "answer": "None", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c74f", "question": "What Greek letter is used to represent electrical resistance?", "answer": "Omega", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133cb0c", "question": "Homichlophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Fog", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c54", "question": "Who wrote \"Brave New World\"?", "answer": "Aldous Huxley", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339bac", "question": "What band's first Top 10 hit in the US was 1984's \"Legs\"?", "answer": "ZZ Top", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe7c943877e98cb977789f2", "question": "Which European capital's harbor is called the Golden Horn?", "answer": "Istanbul's", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c9b", "question": "What John Steinbeck novel gets its title from a lyric in \"The Battle Hymn of the Republic\"?", "answer": "The Grapes of Wrath", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5be580ca5415ba52ed6f0ab9", "question": "Doha is the capital of which West Asian country?", "answer": "Qatar", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b63c", "question": "What liquid did Swiss candle maker Daniel Peter first add to chocolate in 1867?", "answer": "Milk", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fd66029a5bfecdd737e0831", "question": "What percentage of Americans believe in Astrology", "answer": "26", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5fefa4a56ce05a3942286eb6", "question": "What is the name of the cat in the film \"Hocus Pocus\"?", "answer": "Thackery Binx", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133bfbb", "question": "March, April and May are the only months that have what?", "answer": "Anagrams - Charm, Ripal, Yam", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a816", "question": "The two largest islands in the Mediterranean Sea are part of what country?", "answer": "Italy", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e72cbaad0874f1a5e2d1c21", "question": "How many years is a \"Copyright Protection\" granted in the United States to an author after their death?", "answer": "70 years", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f0311339eb0", "question": "What screen legend made her final appearance in the movie \"Autumn Sonata\"?", "answer": "Ingrid Bergman", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a859", "question": "The US state of California was originally part of which Spanish territorial colony?", "answer": "New Spain", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5e38cf45f6c8a670a7957c54", "question": "Including the end zones, how many yards long is the standard American football field?", "answer": "120 yards", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133abc9", "question": "Pretoria is the capital of which African country?", "answer": "South Africa", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c463", "question": "What product that takes its name from a farm animal is a step along the way from iron ore to cast iron?", "answer": "Pig iron", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338c67", "question": "What Stephen King novel features the characters Annie Wilkes and Paul Sheldon?", "answer": "Misery", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5fd66d0ca5bfecdd737e089a", "question": "Which fashion designer is known for his red-soled shoes?", "answer": "Christian Louboutin", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f0311338990", "question": "What Beatrix Potter character has roasted grasshopper for supper after failing to catch minnows?", "answer": "Mr. Jeremy Fisher", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5feddaff6ce05a3942286d8c", "question": "What store in Diagon Alley sells ingredients for potion making?", "answer": "The Apothecary", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c299", "question": "What is the hardest substance in the human body?", "answer": "Enamel", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113393c9", "question": "What TV show featured a character by the name of Christmas Snow?", "answer": "Three's Company", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c37f", "question": "A male duck is properly known as what?", "answer": "A drake", "category": "science"}, {"id": "6015deebfe83fe1f2a824b74", "question": "What countries were involved in the Wars of the Three Kingdoms?", "answer": "England, Ireland, and Scotland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c84f", "question": "In what organ of the human body would you find the bronchi?", "answer": "The lungs", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b8a0", "question": "How many minutes does it take to complete a 12 round boxing match?", "answer": "47 minutes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5febaa287e83c707845b20dc", "question": "What does the ozone layer protect the Earth against?", "answer": "Ultraviolet light", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a55f", "question": "Which state is located directly to the east of Washington D.C.?", "answer": "Maryland", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5fef657b6ce05a3942286e6d", "question": "Where is the oldest annual horse race?", "answer": "England", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f031133917e", "question": "Who is the voice of Woody in the movie series Toy Story?", "answer": "Tom Hanks", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5dde129f031133c0d3", "question": "What former country was Martina Navratilova born in?", "answer": "Czechoslovakia", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5ad7ea28b24f84e0b9f9ffd0", "question": "What is a figure with eight sides called?", "answer": "Octagon", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311339428", "question": "Who played Hank's love interest in the 2001 movie \"Monster's Ball\"?", "answer": "Halle Berry", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5fe8b53101dd7bf43be5e7cc", "question": "What is the name for the process of electing a Pope?", "answer": "Conclave", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b89f", "question": "In what decade did the game \"Monopoly\" go on sale?", "answer": "1930s", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133b09e", "question": "What newspaper was founded in 1889 by Charles H. Dow and Edward Jones?", "answer": "Wall Street Journal", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5b358d015db0d66a186cb55e", "question": "Lisbon lies on which river?", "answer": "Tagus", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5cde129f031133afb0", "question": "Which was the first country to leave the Commonwealth in 1949?", "answer": "Ireland", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe9f03bff048f679a45aa9a", "question": "Podophobia is the fear of what?", "answer": "Feet", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5fe76b3aeec85e375820b2be", "question": "What is the world\u2019s lowest and flattest country?", "answer": "The Maldives", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133aa34", "question": "What is the capital of Italy?", "answer": "Rome", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59071e123745b36be73039e1", "question": "What was the name of the first US human spaceflight?", "answer": "Mercury-Redstone 3, aka Freedom 7", "category": "history"}, {"id": "5fe8b2cc01dd7bf43be5e7a3", "question": "What did Mae Jemison, the first African-American woman to go to space, study while in medical school?", "answer": "Modern dance", "category": "general"}, {"id": "59008fc3cf842fa4c4ba96c0", "question": "Who wrote the epic poem \"Paradise Lost\"?", "answer": "John Milton", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5ffcfdfd9dc5ec6cd98a8327", "question": "Which of Shakespeare's plays features a sorcerer named Prospero?", "answer": "\"The Tempest\"", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "58ab144ebaab681b09292172", "question": "What year did Volkswagen introduce the Golf GTI?", "answer": "1976", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ade129f031133a10a", "question": "\"Need You Tonight\" was a hit for which Australian band?", "answer": "INXS", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "59068023ff9c0647b50a808a", "question": "Which British actor played the role of Spider-Man in the 2016 film \"Captain America: Civil War\"?", "answer": "Tom Holland", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5867fd5bde129f031133a1f9", "question": "Who played Jack Nicholson's wife in the 1980 film \"The Shining\"?", "answer": "Shelley Duvall\u00a0", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "597cd9d5e347d002c297e4cf", "question": "What became the tallest building in London after its official opening in October 1965?", "answer": "Post Office Tower", "category": "geography"}, {"id": "59008d65cf842fa4c4ba96a9", "question": "Who was Liverpool's captain when they won their first European Cup final in 1977?", "answer": "Emlyn Hughes", "category": "general"}, {"id": "5867fd5ede129f031133c9d3", "question": "Which acid is the main gastric acid present in the human stomach?", "answer": "Hydrochloric Acid\u00a0", "category": "science"}, {"id": "5867fd58de129f03113388d7", "question": "In Norse mythology, what was the name of the monster killed by Beowulf?", "answer": "Grendel", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338b66", "question": "What was the first name of Dr. Frankenstein?", "answer": "Victor", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f0311338fa0", "question": "Who is the famous giant slayer during King Arthur times?", "answer": "Jack", "category": "arts"}, {"id": "5867fd59de129f03113394b1", "question": "What was Leonard Nimoy's character's name in Star Trek?", "answer": "Mr. Spock", "category": "entertainment"}, {"id": "5ff51c1aff04d658268c9314", "question": "Father Damien ministered to lepers on which Hawaiian Island?", "answer": "Molokai", "category": "history"}]